Episode 24
에피소드 24
Public security, the skill of making tea...
치안, 차 끓이는 솜씨가...
It's gotten better recently.
최근에는 좋아졌습니다.
As long as dad likes it.
아빠가 좋아하는 한.
I heard that you sold all my stores.
당신이 내 가게를 모두 팔았다는 소식을 들었습니다 .
It's yours. You are free...
그것은 당신의 것입니다. 당신은 무료입니다 ...
Use it however you like.
원하는 대로 사용하세요.
But if you need money...
하지만 돈이 필요하다면...
You can tell your dad
아빠한테 말하면 돼
My brother put up a warning sign...
형이 경고 표시를 해놨어요 ...
At our village shrine...
우리 마을 사당에서...
Are you organized?
정리됐어?
approximately.
약.
Dad said...
아빠가 말씀하셨어요...
Dad will take me and mom...
아빠가 나랑 엄마를 데려갈게...
A vacation to unwind.
긴장을 풀기 위한 휴가.
Are you still willing to do that?
아직도 그렇게 할 의향이 있나요?
Yes, but let's wait a little longer.
응, 하지만 조금만 더 기다려보자.
Your brother's murderer...
네 동생의 살인자...
No arrests have been made yet.
아직 체포되지 않았습니다.
Dad will feel at ease...
아빠는 마음이 편해지실 거에요...
After this incident.
이 사건이 끝난 후.
Please submit this inquiry...
이 문의사항을 제출해 주세요...
To Magistrate Don.
돈 치안 판사에게.
That's his job...
그게 그 사람 직업인데...
So he is more skilled than his father.
그래서 그는 아버지보다 더 능숙합니다.
why?
왜?
You want to go quickly, Qian?
빨리 가고 싶어요, Qian?
This yellow blue is boring.
이 황청은 지루하다.
I don't want to stay here for long.
나는 여기에 오래 머물고 싶지 않습니다.
This is the way.
이것이 방법입니다.
Go for a walk outside the city with your mom.
엄마와 함께 도시 밖으로 산책을 나가보세요 .
I'll look for you in a few days.
며칠 후에 당신을 찾아보겠습니다 .
But I'd rather go...
하지만 차라리 갈래...
with mom and dad
엄마 아빠와 함께
Do you know where to go?
어디로 가야하는지 아시나요?
I want to go to a small town..
작은 마을에 가고 싶다..
South of the Yangtze River.
양쯔강 남쪽.
I heard there are a lot of bridges and rivers ...
다리와 강이 많다고 들었는데 ...
So it's a perfect place to relax .
그래서 휴식을 취하기에 완벽한 장소입니다 .
great.
좋아요.
I will spend a few days trying to get everything done .
나는 모든 것을 끝내기 위해 며칠을 보낼 것입니다 .
After that, my father will resign.
그 후 아버지는 사임하실 것입니다.
Are you serious?
진심인가요?
of.
의.
Dad, I'll go first.
아빠, 저 먼저 갈게요.
great.
좋아요.
I forgot to ask him about Wu Shuomo .
그에게 Wu Shuomo에 대해 물어보는 것을 잊어버렸습니다 .
Forget it. I'll ask that person next time.
잊으세요. 다음에 그 사람에게 물어볼게요.
Kediaman Hua
케디아만 후아
You are busy with official work today.
당신은 오늘 공식적인 업무로 바쁘다 .
I don't think he can make time now .
내 생각엔 그 사람이 지금은 시간을 낼 수 없을 것 같아 .
What do you do when I ask you to come next time?
다음에 오라고 하면 뭐해요?
Because Mr. Jong is busy...
종 씨는 바쁘니까...
I will wait here until he is released.
나는 그가 풀려날 때까지 여기서 기다릴 것입니다 .
Teacher Hua, it's not a good idea to wait here .
Hua 선생님, 여기서 기다리는 것은 좋은 생각이 아닙니다.
What did you answer first?
먼저 뭐라고 대답하셨나요?
I'll go to your house and let you know...
내가 너희 집에 가서 알려줄게...
When Mr. Jong is free.
종 씨가 한가할 때.
I live in Hua Residence.
저는 Hua Residence에 살고 있습니다.
I feel your guilt...
나는 당신의 죄책감을 느낍니다 ...
send me a message
나에게 메세지를 보내
It's okay to wait a while.
잠시 기다려도 괜찮습니다.
Did he go there again?
그 사람 또 거기 갔어?
Yes, it's full.
예, 가득 찼습니다.
That's strange. I think we were pretty close until not long ago.
이상하네요. 얼마 전까지만 해도 꽤 친했던 것 같아요.
But these days, he keeps rejecting my invitations.
그런데 요즘 그 사람이 내 초대를 계속 거절하고 있어요.
Di Mana Qi Ruxin?
디 마나 Qi Ruxin?
Why haven't I seen him these days?
요즘 왜 그 사람을 못 봤지 ?
I was traumatized after hearing that person's words...
그 사람 말을 듣고 트라우마가 생겼어...
During the Mid-Autumn Festival.
중추절 축제 기간 동안 .
So he was still resting in his room.
그래서 그는 여전히 자기 방에서 쉬고 있었습니다.
let's go.
갑시다.
It seems like it's been a while...
오랜만인 것 같은데...
I have not visited your Majesty.
나는 폐하를 방문하지 않았습니다.
But a lot of people come and go.
하지만 많은 사람들이 왔다 갔다 합니다.
When people see you standing here...
당신이 여기 서 있는 걸 사람들이 보면 ...
that ...
그것은 ...
You have gone too far.
당신은 너무 멀리 갔다.
You know I won't allow it...
내가 허락하지 않을 거 알잖아...
People say it's you...
사람들이 너라고 하던데...
So you wait at my door and don't want to leave.
그래서 당신은 내 집 문 앞에서 기다리고 떠나고 싶어하지 않습니다.
You must stay away from me .
당신은 나에게서 떨어져 있어야합니다 .
Do you want to push me again?
또 나를 밀고 싶니?
Please let me know.
알려줘요.
What is the purpose of your visit today?
오늘 방문 목적은 무엇입니까?
You're not mad because you didn't come to me, right?
나한테 안 온다고 화난 건 아니지 ?
But you still seem angry at me...
그런데 아직도 나한테 화난 것 같던데 ...
when i got here
내가 여기 왔을 때
Can you say you're coming for me?
나를 위해 온다고 말할 수 있나요 ?
Came here today...
오늘 여기 왔어요...
to ask for your help
당신의 도움을 요청하기 위해
Sir, please relieve my guard.
선생님, 제 경비를 풀어주세요.
Because in the end , he's still the reason you came.
결국 당신이 온 이유는 여전히 그 사람이기 때문이죠.
In return...
그 대가로...
I'll let me and Dad go...
나랑 아빠는 놓아줄게...
In the matter of my brother Hua Shen.
내 동생 Hua Shen의 문제에서.
You have full control.
당신은 모든 권한을 가지고 있습니다.
What does it mean?
무슨 뜻이에요?
You should know what I mean.
내가 무슨 뜻인지 알아야합니다.
Your guard attacked first.
당신의 경비병이 먼저 공격했습니다.
I don't want to let him go...
그 사람을 보내고 싶지 않아요...
Just because you told me to do it?
단지 네가 나한테 하라고 했기 때문에?
Hwa Yong-ju was wrong...
화용주가 잘못했네...
But you don't need to kill him.
하지만 그를 죽일 필요는 없습니다 .
He suffered a lot as a child.
그는 어렸을 때 많은 고통을 겪었습니다.
I understand if he feels good...
그 사람이 기분이 좋다면 이해해요...
It's hard to find a balance.
균형을 찾기가 어렵습니다.
When he was young?
그가 어렸을 때?
You believe everything he says.
당신은 그의 말을 모두 믿습니다.
Mr. Lee, a wealthy merchant...
부유한 상인 리씨...
Killed many children.
많은 아이들을 죽였습니다.
Her family did not expect Hua Rongzhou ...
그녀의 가족은 Hua Rongzhou를 기대하지 않았습니다 ...
I will risk my life to atone for that sin.
목숨을 걸고 그 죄를 속죄할 것이다 .
Why did you force them to testify against him?
왜 그들에게 그에 대해 불리한 증언을 강요했습니까 ?
He had been in jail for less than five days.
그는 감옥에 갇힌 지 5일도 채 되지 않았습니다.
And coming to Jong Park...
그리고 종공원에 오시다니...
I ask for your help twice.
내 도움을 두 번 요청합니다.
You said he was young.
당신은 그가 어리다고 말했습니다.
That is, at a young age...
즉, 어린 나이...
Give him immunity from punishment?
그에게 처벌 면제를 주나요?
Mr. Li should probably die...
리 씨는 아마도 죽어야 할 것입니다 ...
But Qi Rongzhou took more than one life.
그러나 Qi Rongzhou는 한 번 이상의 목숨을 앗아갔습니다 .
What you mean is...
네 말 뜻은...
Everyone must take responsibility ...
다들 책임져야지 ...
Because of their actions, right?
그들의 행동 때문에 그렇죠?
Meng Libei sent people to kill me...
맹역비는 나를 죽이려고 사람들을 보냈습니다...
But my brother died.
그런데 내 동생이 죽었어.
If you value justice and equality...
정의와 평등을 중시한다면 ...
As you said...
당신이 말했듯이 ...
Why are you hiding this from me?
왜 나 한테 이걸 숨기는 거야?
Why was there someone who missed it...
왜 놓친 사람이 있었나...
When those people killed someone ...
그 사람들이 누군가를 죽였을 때 ...
While others must atone for their crimes...
다른 사람들은 범죄에 대해 속죄해야 하지만...
With their lives?
그들의 삶으로?
How are your parents?
부모님은 잘 계시나요?
Family crab...
패밀리 게...
I have no interest in the law.
법에는 전혀 관심이 없습니다 .
The murder was carried out publicly.
살인은 공개적으로 이루어졌는데..
And they immediately...
그리고 그들은 즉시...
It's rude to the Zhong family.
Zhong 가족에게 무례합니다.
In fact, we caused your brother's death.
사실, 우리가 당신 동생의 죽음을 초래했습니다.
So you think my younger brother is unhappy too...
그럼 너도 내 동생이 불행하다고 생각하는구나...
Did he die because of the commotion?
소동 때문에 죽었나요 ?
I am guilty.
나는 유죄입니다.
I caused your brother's death.
네 동생의 죽음은 내가 초래했다 .
Did you know?
알고 계셨나요?
I became the target of a killer...
살인마의 표적이 됐어...
And Hua Shen died to protect me...
그리고 Hua Shen은 나를 보호하기 위해 죽었습니다 ...
With a knife attack?
칼 공격으로?
I don't know
모르겠어요.
yes. chaos...
예. 혼돈...
At the Mid-Autumn Festival banquet.
중추절 연회 에서 .
Everyone ran away .
모두가 도망쳤다 .
No one noticed anything different.
아무도 다른 것을 눈치 채지 못했습니다.
As one of the planners, you too...
기획자 중 한 분인 당신도 ...
Also, I don't know what happened.
또한 무슨 일이 일어났는지 모른다.
How would anyone else know?
다른 사람이 어떻게 알겠어요?
Prosecution investigation...
검찰 수사…
Controlled by bureaucracy.
관료주의에 의해 통제됩니다.
It's faster if I do my own research.
내가 직접 조사하는 게 더 빠르다 .
In the end, I became the assassin's target...
결국 나는 암살자의 표적이 되었다...
So I won't let that person go easily .
그러니 그 사람을 쉽게 놓아주지 않을 거예요 .
Miss Hua, you are very brave and smart.
Miss Hua, 당신은 매우 용감하고 똑똑합니다.
I can't believe I'm writing this...
이걸 쓰다니...
Do you want to make a deal with me now?
지금 나랑 거래할까 ?
So you already know.
그래서 당신은 이미 알고 있습니다.
I can tell something...
뭔가 알 수 있어...
About the murder at the banquet.
연회에서의 살인에 대해.
During holidays...
명절때..
Nothing is out of the ordinary...
뭐 하나도 평범하지 않은데...
About Hwangcheong's bodyguards.
황청의 경호원에 대해 .
only...
단지...
progress.
진행하다.
A few days before the holidays...
명절을 며칠 앞둔...
Southern maid mung...
남쪽의 메이드 멍...
And to the north is Maid Qi.
그리고 북쪽에는 Maid Qi가 있습니다.
Send people to deliver gifts.
사람들을 보내 선물을 배달하세요.
Why the Meng family?
왜 멩 가족인가?
Meng has more than 20 aides…
멍의 보좌관은 20명이 넘는데…
He returns to the village with his wife and child .
그의 아내와 아이를 데리고 마을로 돌아갑니다.
In the meantime, they also sent gifts and snacks...
그 사이에 선물과 간식 도 보내주셨는데 ...
Chuseok prepared by her .
그녀가 준비한 추석 .
The person who received it was Master Maeng Du.
그것을 받은 사람은 맹두선사였습니다 .
Until the third day after the holiday...
명절이 끝난 후 사흘째 되는 날까지 ...
20 people left the village...
20명이 마을을 떠났는데...
And then head back south.
그리고 남쪽으로 돌아갑니다.
According to a spy from the Meng family...
맹씨 가문의 스파이에 따르면 ...
Half of them are foreigners...
절반이 외국인인데..
I'm not even the one sending the gifts.
선물을 보내는 사람도 아닙니다 .
Can we trust what the spy says?
스파이의 말을 믿을 수 있을까 ?
If you're not sure if you're a spy...
스파이가 확실하지 않다면...
They won't report to us.
그들은 우리에게 보고하지 않을 것입니다.
In the end, it didn't make sense...
결국 말이 안 되더라구요...
Waiting too long...
너무 오래 기다리다...
After delivery is completed.
배송이 완료된 후.
With all the recent events...
최근의 모든 사건들과 함께...
Their strange behavior woke me up.
그들의 이상한 행동이 나를 깨웠다.
There's nothing complicated.
복잡한 것은 없습니다.
Why did it take me so long to find out?
왜 아는 데 그렇게 오랜 시간이 걸렸나요?
The person who sent the gift...
선물을 보낸 사람..
Suspicious person from the Qi family ...
Qi 가문의 의심스러운 인물..
So I spend a lot of time...
그래서 시간을 많이 보내는데...
Research the Qi family.
Qi 가족을 조사하세요.
Finally I found out...
마침내 나는 알게 되었다...
That man and Miss Chi...
그 남자와 미스 치...
There is a relationship.
관계가 있습니다.
He had nothing to do with the murder.
그는 살인과 아무 관련이 없습니다 .
I knew from the beginning.
나는 처음부터 알고 있었다.
It was clear that Qi Ruxin was strange.
Qi Ruxin이 이상한 것이 분명했습니다.
I never thought it would make me lose focus .
집중력을 잃게 만들 거라고는 생각하지 못했습니다 .
Teacher, please forgive me!
선생님, 용서해주세요!
You investigated the Meng family guards...
멩 가문 경비병들을 조사하셨습니다 ...
Who sent the gift?
누가 선물을 보냈나요?
I sent people south...
내가 사람들을 남쪽으로 보냈는데...
I'm trying to investigate secretly.
비밀리에 조사를 하려고 합니다.
Their findings...
그들의 조사 결과는...
A security guard was killed by a robber .
경비원이 강도에게 살해당했습니다 .
Before you get to the store in the south.
남쪽에 있는 상점 에 도착하기 전에요 .
After the meng tide...
멍 조수 이후에 ...
You may also know about this...
이것에 대해 알 수도 있습니다 ...
He also hires people...
그 사람도 사람 고용하는데...
To get rid of the robbers .
강도를 없애기 위해 .
But that information came from a spy...
하지만 그 정보는 스파이에게서 나온 것인데...
And there are no witnesses.
그리고 증인도 없어요.
How dare you?
어떻게 감히?
Are they really brave?
그들은 정말로 용감한가?
Many things...
많은 것들...
It's not as easy as you think.
생각만큼 쉽지는 않습니다.
I'll keep it short.
짧게 말하겠습니다.
Jangan Beoneo Hwayongju...
장안번어화용주...
I won't even open my mouth about Meng Yeobi...
맹역비에 대해서는 입도 열지 않겠습니다 ...
my whole life
내 평생
Are security guards really important to you?
경비원이 당신에게 정말 중요 합니까?
That's not the problem.
그게 문제가 아니예요.
There aren't many people around me...
제 주변에는 사람이 별로 없어요...
Treat me sincerely...
진심으로 대해줘...
So I am thankful for people who treat me well.
그래서 나에게 잘 대해주는 사람들이 고맙다 .
how about me
나는 어때
Don't you know how I treat you?
내가 당신을 대하는 방식을 모르시나요 ?
Why if I notice?
내가 눈치채면 왜?
I made it clear from the beginning.
나는 처음부터 분명히 말했습니다 .
Tuan is the head of the Zhong Family.
Tuan은 Zhong Family의 우두머리입니다.
You have great responsibility for producing ...
당신은 생산에 큰 책임이 있습니다 ...
Good for your health.
건강에 좋은.
You always put business first...
항상 사업을 최우선으로 생각하시네요...
In a relationship with a woman.
여자와의 관계에서 .
- I just... - You already know...
- 난 그냥... - 이미 알고 있잖아...
Meng Yifei is one of the people behind it.
Meng Yifei는 배후 인물 중 한 명입니다.
Behind the banquet murder...
연회 살인의 배후..
And how many times have you tried to stop me...
그리고 당신은 몇 번이나 나를 말리려고 했어요...
meet him
그를 만나서.
Aren’t you afraid I might find out?
내가 알게 될까 두렵지 않나요?
The Meng family will be repaid.
Meng 가족은 상환받을 것입니다.
I can guarantee that.
나는 그것을 보장할 수 있다.
But it's not time yet.
하지만 아직은 때가 아니다.
I know why.
나는 이유를 안다.
The Meng family holds the operating rights...
Meng 가족은 운영권을 보유하고 있습니다 ...
Shops in the south.
남쪽에 있는 상점들.
Forced coup…
강제 쿠데타…
It only weakens the power of the family...
가족의 힘만 약화될 뿐입니다 ...
And give others a chance too...
그리고 다른 사람들에게도 기회를 주세요...
To take a chance.
기회를 잡으려고.
I know you have your reasons ...
당신에게도 나름의 이유가 있다는 걸 알아요 ...
So that Meng Yifei and Qi Ruxin can stay...
Meng Yifei와 Qi Ruxin이 머물 수 있도록 ...
Di Taman species.
디 타만 종.
Therefore you can't do anything to them.
그러므로 당신은 그들에게 아무것도 할 수 없습니다 .
I understand too...
나도 이해해...
You can't do whatever you want...
마음대로 할 수는 없잖아...
When you have power.
힘이 있을 때.
But it turns out...
하지만 알고보니...
That doesn't mean I agree with your actions.
그렇다고 내가 당신의 행동에 동의한다는 뜻은 아닙니다 .
Kian...
키안...
Even though you are a big shot...
비록 당신은 거물이지만 ...
Justice cannot be guaranteed in all respects.
모든 면에서 정의를 보장할 수는 없습니다 .
Everyone has their own reasons.
누구나 자신만의 이유가 있습니다.
If you release Huarongzhou...
화룽저우를 풀어주면...
I will convince my father to resign...
아버지를 설득해 사임하겠다…
And we will return to the village.
그리고 우리는 마을로 돌아갈 것이다.
We will no longer investigate Meng Lifei's affairs.
우리는 더 이상 맹역비의 일을 조사하지 않을 것입니다 .
you don't want to go
당신은 가고 싶지 않습니다
I didn't think you wanted to go.
나는 당신이 가고 싶어한다고 생각하지 않았습니다.
Only I know what Meng Yifei did .
맹역비가 무슨 일을 했는지는 나만이 안다 .
If you don't believe me...
나를 믿지 않는다면...
Teacher, can you please shut my mouth...
선생님 제 입 좀 다물어 주실 수 있나요...
And free the rest.
그리고 나머지는 풀어주세요.
I have said this many times.
나는 여러 번 말했습니다.
I never made any assumptions about you...
나는 당신에 대해 추측을 한 적이 없습니다 ...
But you don't want to believe me
하지만 당신은 내 말을 믿고 싶어하지 않는군요
great.
좋아요.
then...
그렇다면...
I won't waste any more time.
더 이상 시간을 낭비하지 않겠습니다.
But know...
하지만 알아둬...
I agree to all your requests...
나는 당신의 모든 요청에 ​​동의합니다 ...
Other than taking the guards with you...
경비병을 데리고 가는 것 외에는 ...
I live outside Huangcheng!
Huangcheng 밖에서 살아요!
I won't allow it!
나는 그것을 허용하지 않을 것이다!
Teacher, what are you saying?
선생님 무슨 말씀이신가요?
Perjanjian antara Qian Ying dan Mu Yunping
Perjanjian antara Qian Ying dan Mu Yunping
Evidence of my father's crime...
아버지 범죄의 증거..
What you have is just a copy.
당신이 갖고 있는 것은 단지 사본일 뿐입니다.
You really think I don't know...
내가 정말 모른다고 생각하는구나 ...
What did your father do?
네 아버지는 무슨 일을 하셨나요?
You take good care of my jewelry.
당신은 내 보석을 잘 관리합니다.
Do you remember the white jade bracelet...
백옥팔찌 기억하시나요...
Did he give it to me when I got married?
내가 결혼할 때 그 사람이 나한테 준 거요 ?
Yes, I remember.
네 기억합니다.
Please let me look for it.
제가 찾아보도록 해주세요.
I want to go to Taman Zhong tomorrow.
내일 Taman Zhong에 가고 싶어요.
I have to send it back.
나는 그것을 돌려보내야 한다.
Okay, ma'am.
좋아요, 부인.
Yixingxing is the owner.
이싱싱이 주인입니다.
Why does the person seem to have changed?
왜 그 사람은 변한 것처럼 보일까요?
Maybe he will get better...
어쩌면 그 사람은 나아질지도 모르지...
After his wish came true.
그의 소원이 이루어진 후.
yes?
예?
I think we should look into it.
내 생각엔 우리가 조사해야 할 것 같아.
Choose a smart girl at Zhong Residence...
Zhong Residence에서 똑똑한 여자를 선택하세요 ...
And I set him aside.
그리고 그를 옆에 두었습니다.
Have a nice day, madam. My name is Yixingxing.
좋은 하루 보내세요, 부인. 저는 이싱싱이에요.
I told you earlier that I don't trust you.
아까 내가 당신을 믿지 않는다고 말했잖아요.
I thought you didn't include it...
안 넣은 줄 알았는데...
The spy next to me.
내 옆에 있는 스파이.
I have to do this every time I go out...
나갈 때마다 해야지...
See you outside.
밖에서 뵙겠습니다.
i know...
알아요...
No matter how much I defend...
내가 아무리 변호해도...
you won't trust me anymore
당신은 더 이상 나를 믿지 않을 것입니다
But it's impossible for you and assistant Hua ...
하지만 당신과 Hua 조수에게는 불가능합니다 ...
You can leave Hwangcheong...
황청을 떠날 수 있다...
No worries.
걱정 없이.
great.
좋아요.
You have complete control over us.
당신은 우리를 완전히 통제하고 있습니다.
Tracing a colleague is also a serious crime.
동료를 함정에 빠뜨리는 것도 심각한 범죄입니다.
What do you mean, bring me death?
나에게 죽음을 안겨준다는 게 무슨 말이야 ?
Is it enough to atone for the sins of the father?
아버지의 죄를 속죄하기 에 충분합니까 ?
You know what I'm thinking...
내가 무슨 생각하는지 알잖아...
But you said that to make me angry.
그런데 당신은 나를 화나게 하려고 그런 말을 했어요.
Teacher, do you know what I think?
선생님 생각은 알겠어요?
Jong Si-woo.
종시우.
No, I have no idea what you're thinking .
아니요, 저는 당신의 생각을 전혀 모릅니다 .
It shows that you shouldn't make it...
만들지 말라는 걸 보여주네요...
Assistant Hua is in charge.
Hua 어시스턴트가 담당하고 있습니다.
So for what?
그래서 무엇을 위해?
You said...
당신은 말했다 ...
We will stop investigating the Meng Lifei incident...
맹역비 사건 수사를 중단하겠습니다 ...
In exchange for the safety of the guards.
경비원의 안전을 대가로 .
I will allow...
허락하겠습니다...
Just reveal the truth...
진실을 밝히기만 하면...
About Assistant Hua abusing his colleagues...
Hua 어시스턴트가 동료들을 학대한 것에 대해...
To make sure he was safe.
그가 안전한지 확인하기 위해.
why me?
왜 내가?
Didn't you collect any evidence?
증거를 수집하지 않았나요?
You will find out later.
나중에 알게 될 것입니다.
On the 5th of next month...
다음달 5일..
I will call all the helpers in this city ...
이 도시의 모든 도우미를 불러오겠습니다 ...
To attend a banquet held at Zhong Park .
종공원(Zhong Park)에서 열리는 연회에 참석하기 위해 .
If you disclose this fact in front of those people...
이 사실을 그 사람들 앞에서 공개하면 ...
I will free your family.
나는 당신의 가족을 풀어줄 것입니다.
You think this is like a game.
당신은 이것이 게임과 같다고 생각합니다.
Should I hide my mistakes or reveal them...
실수를 숨길지, 드러낼지...
It's up to you.
그것은 당신에게 달려 있습니다.
Kian...
키안...
I will take your word for it.
나는 당신의 말을 받아들이겠습니다.
I’m going to pick up Hua Rongzhou now.
지금 Hua Rongzhou를 데리러 갈 것입니다 .
On the 5th of next month...
다음달 5일..
I will do as you said.
나는 당신이 말한대로 할 것입니다.
Pull out the insing...
인싱 풀라...
please call that person again
그 사람에게 다시 전화해 주세요
I'm scared when I think of the results...
결과를 생각하면 두렵다...
If I protect that person
내가 그 사람을 지켜준다면
Qian, believe it or not. Whatever I make...
퀴안, 믿거나 말거나. 내가 뭘 만들든...
I did it to make sure you were by my side.
당신이 내 곁에 있는지 확인하기 위해 그랬어요 .
Kian!
키안!
Let's go to jail first.
먼저 감옥에 가자.
Yes, it's full.
예, 가득 찼습니다.
Go to jail before you come back...
돌아오기 전에 감옥에 가세요...
Kediaman arose.
케케디아만(Kediaman)이 일어났습니다.
Let's see.
어디 보자.
Buy one.
하나 사.
This basket is durable.
이 바구니는 내구성이 좋습니다.
Let's see.
어디 보자.
What is this?
이건 뭐죠?
Evolutionary powder, pain reliever.
진화분말, 진통제.
I was hurt because of you...
너 때문에 상처받았어...
So you have to give me medicine .
그러니까 당신이 나한테 약을 발라줘야 해요 .
The light did not arrive.
등이 도착하지 않았습니다.
follow me.
날 따라와.
Get out.
나가세요.
I'm here to get you.
나는 당신을 데리러 왔습니다.
What happened to you?
당신에게 무슨 일이 일어났나요?
Miss, you don't look well.
아가씨 몸이 안 좋아 보여요.
I like it.
내가 좋아입니다.
Miss cheating.
미스 부정 행위.
The lady is not good at cheating.
아가씨는 바람피우는 걸 잘 못해요.
You don't have to say anything if you don't want to.
원하지 않으면 말하지 않아도 됩니다 .
Aren't you smart?
당신은 똑똑하지 않나요?
Huarongzhou...
화룽저우...
Why does it look different than before?
왜 예전과 다르게 보이죠 ?
What's different?
무엇이 다른가요?
Guard Fire, this is your sword.
경비병 화여, 이것이 당신의 검입니다.
I brought it here for you.
나는 당신을 위해 그것을 여기로 가져왔습니다.
Lady, I took a shower.
아가씨, 나 샤워했어요.
This is money and food.
이것은 돈이고 음식이다.
You didn't even sign a contract...
계약도 안 하시고...
So I prepared all of this.
그래서 이걸 다 준비했어요.
Murder is still wrong.
살인은 여전히 ​​​​잘못입니다.
I did my best to save you ...
나는 당신을 구하기 위해 최선을 다했습니다 ...
This time, starting with punishment.
이번에는 처벌부터.
From now on, look for another job.
이제부터 다른 직업을 찾아보세요.
Miss said once...
미스님이 한 번 말씀하셨는데...
They won't let me live alone ...
나 혼자 살게 놔두지 않을 텐데 ...
But now you want to leave me ?
그런데 이제 나를 떠나고 싶어 ?
of.
의.
Shortcuts.
바로 가기.
We've known each other for a long time...
우리는 오랫동안 서로를 알고 있었습니다...
So we will part ways amicably.
그래서 우리는 우호적으로 헤어질 것입니다.
Please don't let me kick you out.
내가 당신을 쫓아내지 못하게 해주세요.
There is no one in Hua Residence to compare with me.
Hua Residence에는 나와 비교할 사람이 없습니다 .
So if I want to stay here...
그러니 내가 여기에 머물고 싶다면...
No one can kick me out.
아무도 나를 쫓아낼 수 없습니다.
Say it again.
다시 말해보세요.
Does this mean you can now disobey my orders?
이제 내 명령을 거역할 수 있다는 뜻인가요 ?
One time Miss said she would come with me.
한번은 Miss가 나와 함께 가겠다고 말했어요.
At the prison entrance...
감옥 입구에서..
My aunt said she came to pick me up.
이모는 이모가 나를 데리러 왔다고 했어요.
I believe every word you say.
나는 당신이 말하는 모든 말을 믿습니다.
Why did you break your promise?
왜 약속을 어겼나요?
Things are different now. I have...
이제는 달라졌습니다. 나는 가지고있다...
My previous actions were to protect myself.
나의 이전 행동은 나 자신을 보호하기 위한 것이었습니다.
I have never intentionally caused trouble...
고의로 문제를 일으킨 적은 한번도 없습니다 ...
Or hurt someone.
아니면 누군가에게 상처를 주거나.
If you're angry about my past mistakes ...
내 과거의 잘못 에 대해 화를 낸다면 ...
I promise...
약속해요...
I won't do that again...
다시는 그러지 않을게요...
Unless instructed to do so.
지시를 내리지 않는 한.
If you don't believe me...
나를 믿지 않는다면...
My right hand is going to be paralyzed...
오른손이 마비되겠다 ...
To show my resolve.
내 결심을 보여주기 위해.
Anyway, I learned martial arts...
아무튼 무술을 배웠는데...
It is not for revenge or to harass the weak.
복수 하거나 약자를 괴롭히기 위해서가 아니다 .
Now I use it to protect you.
이제 나는 당신을 보호하기 위해 그것을 사용합니다.
If you don't want me here...
내가 여기 있는 걸 원하지 않는다면...
My martial arts skills are useless.
내 무술 실력은 쓸모가 없어.
You lied to me.
당신은 나에게 거짓말을 했어요.
When you leave Hwangcheong ...
황청을 떠나면 ...
Lady, it's only me.
아가씨, 나밖에 없어요.
So don't look for an excuse to kick me out.
그러니 나를 쫓아낼 핑계를 찾지 마세요 .
I don't want you to be alone.
나는 당신이 혼자 있는 것을 원하지 않습니다.
For me...
나를 위한...
All this time, there was only you by my side.
그동안 내 옆에는 너밖에 없었어 .
when i see you
당신을 보면
I can't trust you if I entrust you with something important, right?
중요한 일을 맡기면 당신을 믿을 수 없겠죠 ?
I will improve myself.
나는 나 자신을 향상시킬 것이다.
OK. I won't kick you out.
괜찮은. 나는 당신을 쫓아 내지 않을 것입니다.
Thank you, ma’am.
감사합니다 사모님.
You may go now.
이제 가셔도 됩니다.
Yes, it's full.
예, 가득 찼습니다.
That person is just as stubborn as me...
그 사람도 나만큼 고집이 센데...
In my past life
전생에서
But the best thing for him is to leave here.
하지만 그에게 가장 좋은 방법은 여기를 떠나는 것입니다.
Forget it I'll think of another way.
잊으세요. 다른 방법을 생각해 보겠습니다.
Have you seen YixingSing?
이싱싱 봤어?
I didn't see him today.
나는 오늘 그를 보지 못했습니다.
I told him to go.
나는 그에게 가라고 말했습니다.
What did he do?
그는 무엇을 했나요?
It's the same reason I told Cuizhu to leave.
내가 Cuizhu에게 떠나라고 말한 것과 같은 이유입니다 .
It seems we can't trust the maid...
우리는 하녀를 믿을 수 없는 것 같습니다 ...
In our area.
우리 지역에서.
Miss, don't worry.
아가씨, 걱정하지 마세요.
I won't betray you.
나는 당신을 배신하지 않을 것입니다.
Unable to.
할 수 없습니다.
Nanfeng may come looking for you.
Nanfeng이 당신을 찾으러 올 수도 있습니다 .
Why didn't you run when your face was red?
얼굴이 빨개진 채 왜 뛰지 않았나요 ?
Say whatever you want.
원하는 대로 말하세요.
I'm used to it.
나는 그것에 익숙하다.
Another fun craft is missing.
또 다른 재미있는 만들기가 빠졌습니다 .
Find someone to send to...
보낼 사람을 찾아보세요 ...
What are you waiting for? fast.
당신은 무엇을 기다리고 있습니까? 빠른.
- Don't be late. - Miss, that person...
- 늦지 말아라. - 아가씨, 그 사람은...
sun. fast.
해. 빠른.
go away.
저리 가요.
Bring a bottle of special black wine ...
스페셜 블랙 와인 한 병을 가져오세요 ...
And come with me.
그리고 나와 함께 가세요.
Okay, ma'am.
좋아요, 부인.
Qubur Huashen
쿠부르 후아셴
This is a special black wine. My sister's favorite.
스페셜 블랙와인 입니다. 내 동생이 가장 좋아하는 것.
Does it smell good, Shen?
좋은 냄새 나니, 쉔?
I'm not good at drinking alcohol...
저는 술을 잘 못마셔요..
So let's drink later.
그러니 나중에 마시자.
Let me tell you what I want to say first.
제가 하고 싶은 말을 먼저 말씀드리겠습니다 .
Please forgive me, brother.
용서해주세요, 형제님.
I'm here to apologize again.
또 사과하러 왔습니다 .
I can not...
난 못해...
File a lawsuit for your brother's death...
동생의 죽음에 대해 소송을 제기하다...
Even though I know the culprit.
비록 내가 범인을 알고 있음에도 불구하고.
After all, there are North Korean defectors among you.
역시 여러분 중에는 탈북자가 있습니다.
We failed to do our duty.
우리는 의무를 다하지 못했습니다.
When our master returns...
우리 주인님이 돌아오시면...
We will offer our lives as a ransom.
우리의 생명을 대속물로 바치겠습니다 .
I will suspend my sentence...
형을 유예하겠습니다...
Until your master returns.
네 주인이 돌아올 때까지.
Leave the traitor to me...
배신자는 나에게 맡겨라...
So that you can get your master back .
네 주인을 되찾을 수 있게 .
We use several technologies...
우리는 여러 가지 기술을 사용합니다...
Under interrogation.
심문 중.
He cannot stand torture...
그는 고문을 참지 못한다...
and died
그리고 죽었어
Do you want your master back or not?
당신은 당신의 주인이 돌아오기를 원합니까 , 아니면 원하지 않습니까?
Please forgive me, Mrs. Mu.
용서해주세요, 무 여사님.
We can't...
우리는 할 수 없습니다 ...
Please hand over the North Korean defector.
탈북자를 넘겨주세요.
why?
왜?
Our master is planning to kidnap the banquet...
우리 주인님이 연회 납치를 계획하고 계시는데...
because I missed you
그리워서
It has to be a secret plan.
비밀 계획이어야 합니다.
We do it under the guise of Family Ge...
우리는 Family Ge를 가장하여 그것을 합니다 ...
So that no one doubts us .
아무도 우리를 의심하지 않도록 .
Who would have thought that someone would die?
누군가가 죽을 것이라고 누가 생각이나 했을까요?
If only people knew about Wooyoung...
우영씨를 사람들이 알았더라면 ...
They are trying to kill Hua's helper son...
후아의 도우미 아들을 죽이려고 하는데 ...
Our lord will be considered the cause of this...
우리 영주님이 이 일의 원인으로 여겨질 것입니다 ...
Hostility between two families...
두 가족 사이의 적대감..
Even though our master...
비록 우리 주인님은...
I want to kidnap Hua Chen...
화첸을 납치하고 싶다...
And didn't kill anyone.
그리고 누구도 죽이지 않았습니다.
The culprit was someone else.
범인은 다른 사람이었습니다.
But no one cares about the details.
그러나 아무도 세부 사항에 관심이 없습니다.
Our master is stubborn...
우리 주인님은 고집이 세세요...
And I insist that you take risks.
그리고 위험을 감수해야 한다고 주장합니다.
We have no choice but to obey.
우리는 순종할 수 밖에 없습니다.
If I get caught, I will commit suicide...
잡히면 자살하겠다...
And didn't say anything.
그리고 아무 말도 하지 않았습니다.
However, there are North Korean defectors among us.
그런데 우리 중에 탈북자도 있어요 .
He put our master's life in danger.
그는 우리 주인의 생명을 위험에 빠뜨렸습니다.
No matter what happens, we can't give up on him...
무슨 일이 있어도 우리는 그 사람을 포기할 수 없어요...
Provides information.
정보를 제공합니다.
so...
그래서...
You can just say...
그냥 말해도 돼...
Who caused Hua Shen's death?
Hua Shen의 죽음을 초래한 사람은 누구입니까 ?
great.
좋아요.
Do you think...
당신 생각엔...
Will Hua Qian be satisfied with this answer?
Hua Qian은 이 답변에 만족할까요 ?
Could you please send him a letter first?
그에게 먼저 편지를 보내 주시겠어요 ?
If the person is smart, he will understand.
그 사람이 똑똑하다면 이해할 것이다.
But if Hua Qian insists...
하지만 Hua Qian이 주장한다면 ...
I don't want to lose my master...
우리 주인님을 놓치고 싶지 않아...
We had to...
우린 그래야했다...
Risking your life to save him.
그를 구하기 위해 목숨을 걸고 .
Sir, Mu Yao has sent someone to deliver this letter.
선생님, Mu Yao가 이 편지를 전달하기 위해 사람을 보냈습니다.
Mu Yao wrote a letter to me...
무야오가 나에게 편지를 썼다...
And he said we all know the truth.
그리고 우리 모두가 진실을 알고 있다고 말했습니다.
But we have to pretend not to know...
하지만 우리는 모르는 척 해야 해...
Because there is no evidence.
증거가 없기 때문입니다.
We found no evidence...
우리는 증거를 찾지 못했습니다 ...
Because it's a murderer...
살인자니까...
Protect other killers.
다른 살인자를 보호하십시오.
The only one who can perform ...
공연을 할 수 있는 유일한 사람 ..
Pretend you don’t even know that.
그것도 모르는 척.
Brother, I can't do anything else.
형님, 저는 다른 일을 할 수 없습니다.
This world is unfair.
이 세상은 불공평해요.
Relationships take precedence over the law.
관계가 법보다 우선합니다.
Blood debts are paid with blood...
피의 빚은 피로 갚는다…
It only applies to the lower classes of society.
사회의 낮은 계층 에게만 해당됩니다 .
For some people, killing someone...
어떤 사람들에게는 사람을 죽이는 일이...
It's as easy as killing ants.
개미를 죽이는 것만큼 쉽습니다.
For some, seeking justice...
누군가에게는 정의를 추구하는...
Like swimming upstream.
상류로 수영하는 것처럼요.
sibling.
형제.
Please forgive.
용서 해줘.
I can't risk my life...
목숨을 걸고 는 할 수 없어 ...
To take down Meng Yifei.
Meng Yifei를 쓰러뜨리기 위해.
Only I can write it...
나만 쓸 수 있는데...
The information I heard...
내가 들은 정보는..
In return...
그 대가로…
for the benefit of
...의 이익을 위해
Painter family.
화가족.
Am I so mean?
내가 너무 못됐나요?
After being reborn...
다시 태어난 후...
I think...
제 생각에는...
I'm far away from all of you...
난 너희들과 모두 멀리 떨어져 있어...
You can avoid repeating the same mistakes.
같은 실수를 반복 하지 않을 수 있어요 .
Now it seems like that...
이제 그럴 것 같습니다 ...
I was wrong.
내가 틀렸어.
this...
이것...
Secondly I was wrong.
두 번째로 내가 틀렸어요.
Do you know?
당신은 알고 있나요?
I saw my brother die in front of me twice.
나는 내 앞에서 형이 죽는 것을 두 번이나 보았다.
Don't worry, brother.
걱정하지 마세요, 형제님.
I'm going to make things difficult...
일을 어렵게 만들겠다...
That person.
저 사람.
me...
나...
It's inherently evil.
원래 악해요.
How much.
얼마나 많이.
sibling.
형제.
Lakaman Bonus
라카만 보너스
Aren't you smart?
당신은 똑똑하지 않나요?
Be careful of injuries.
부상에 주의하세요.
welcome.
어서오세요.